A Guide to the Melvin Feldenheimer Collection, 1940-1997
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Melvin Feldenheimer Collection, 1940-1997
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2008-083
0.1 cu. ft. 1 folder
Melvin Feldenheimer graduated from the Virginia Tech in 1944. Collection consists of materials from Feldenheimer's time as a cadet at Virginia Tech. Also included is a recording from a 1946 performance of Mel Felton and the Southern Colonels, a dance band lead by Feldenheimer during his time as a student and following World War II the band reunited and toured the south.
Feldenheimer, Melvin
Adminstrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Melvin Feldenheimer Collection was donated to the University Archives in Special Collections in 1997.
Biographical Information
Melvin Feldenheimer graduated from the Virginia Polytechnic Institute in 1944. While attending VPI he was the band leader of the Southern Colonels. The band became very popular following World War II and they toured the south under the name "Mel Felton and the Southern Colonels." In 1946 the band was featured on the radio station WCSC in South Carolina. A copy of this broadcast is included with the collection.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of a recording of an August 1946 performance by Mel Felton and the Southern Colonels as well as materials from Melvin Feldenheimer's time as a cadet at VPI. Materials include dance tickets, event programs, and two photographs. The collection also contains photocopies of newspaper clippings about Mel Felton and the Southern Colonels as well as a photocopy of a poster advertising a performance by the band. An article from the Fall 1997 Virginia Tech Magazine about the Southern Colonels is included as well as a letter praising the 1946 recording.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by material type.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
Mel Felton and the Southern Colonels Recordings, Ms2016-002. Finding ai d available online.
Index Terms
Persons:
Feldenheimer, Melvin
Subjects:
University Archives; Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Contents List
- Virginia Polytechnic Institute Christmas Card, 1940 (Folder 1)
- Student Identification Card, 1940-1941 (Folder 1)
- Class of 1944 Freshman Banquet Program, 1941 (Folder 1)
- German Club - Opening Dance Ticket, 1941 (Folder 1)
- Ring Dance Ticket, 1942 (Folder 1)
- Class of 1944 Ring Dance Advertisement, 1942 (Folder 1)
- Mel Felton and the Southern Colonels recording, 1946 (Folder 1)
- Article from Virginia Tech Magazine, Fall 1997 (Folder 1)
- Letter regarding 1946 recording, October 20, 1997 (Folder 1)
- Unidentified Photographs (Folder 1)
- Mel Felton and the Southern Colonels Poster (Folder 1)
- Newspaper Clippings (Folder 1)